<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<NewsItem>
	<Title>The first modern automobile</Title>
  <MetaTitle>The first modern automobile</MetaTitle>
  <Short>Cars came into global use during the 20th century, making developed economies dependent on them. The year 1886 is regarded as the birth year of the modern car when German inventor Karl Benz patented his Benz Patent-Motorwagen.</Short>
	<MetaDescription>Cars came into global use during the 20th century, making developed economies dependent on them. The year 1886 is regarded as the birth year of the modern car when German inventor Karl Benz patented his Benz Patent-Motorwagen.</MetaDescription>
  <Full>
		<![CDATA[
			<p>
				Cars came into global use during the 20th century, and developed economies depend on them. The year 1886 is regarded as the birth year
				of the modern car when German inventor Karl Benz patented his Benz Patent-Motorwagen. Cars became widely available in the early 20th
				century. One of the first cars accessible to the masses was the 1908 Model T, an American car manufactured by the Ford Motor Company. Cars
				were rapidly adopted in the US, where they replaced animal-drawn carriages and carts, but took much longer to be accepted in Western
				Europe and other parts of the world.
      </p>
			<p>
				In November 1881, French inventor Gustave Trouvé demonstrated the first working (three-wheeled) car powered by electricity at the
				International Exposition of Electricity, Paris. Although several other German engineers (including Gottlieb Daimler, Wilhelm Maybach, and
				Siegfried Marcus) were working on the problem at about the same time, Karl Benz generally is acknowledged as the inventor of the modern car.
      </p>
			<p>
				The original Benz Patent-Motorwagen, first built in 1885 and awarded the patent for the concept In 1879, Benz was granted a patent for
				his first engine, which had been designed in 1878. Many of his other inventions made the use of the internal combustion engine feasible
				for powering a vehicle. His first Motorwagen was built in 1885 in Mannheim, Germany. He was awarded the patent for its invention as of his
				application on 29 January 1886 (under the auspices of his major company, Benz &amp; Cie., which was founded in 1883). Benz began promotion
				of the vehicle on 3 July 1886, and about 25 Benz vehicles were sold between 1888 and 1893, when his first four-wheeler was introduced
				along with a cheaper model. They also were powered with four-stroke engines of his own design. Emile Roger of France, already producing
				Benz engines under license, now added the Benz car to his line of products. Because France was more open to the early cars, initially more
				were built and sold in France through Roger than Benz sold in Germany. In August 1888 Bertha Benz, the wife of Karl Benz, undertook the
				first road trip by car, to prove the road-worthiness of her husband's invention.
      </p>
		]]>
	</Full>
	<CreatedOn>2020-09-07</CreatedOn>
	<Image>benz-first-modern-car.jpg</Image>
  <ImagePreview>benz-first-modern-car.jpg</ImagePreview>
	<Comments>True</Comments>
</NewsItem>