<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<BlogPost>
	<Title>America's Sports Car: Chevrolet Corvette</Title>
  <MetaTitle>America's Sports Car: Chevrolet Corvette</MetaTitle>
	<Intro>The Chevrolet Corvette, colloquially known as the "Vette", is a two-door, two-passenger sports car manufactured and marketed by Chevrolet across more than 60 years of production and eight design generations. The Corvette has since become widely known as "America's Sports Car."</Intro>
	<MetaDescription>The Chevrolet Corvette, colloquially known as the "Vette", is a two-door, two-passenger sports car manufactured and marketed by Chevrolet across more than 60 years of production and eight design generations. The Corvette has since become widely known as "America's Sports Car."</MetaDescription>
	<Body>
		<![CDATA[
			<p>
				The Chevrolet Corvette, colloquially known as the "Vette", is a two-door, two-passenger sports car manufactured and marketed by
				Chevrolet across more than 60 years of production and eight design generations. From 1953 to 2019, it was front-engined, and since 2020,
				it is mid-engined. With its generations noted sequentially from C1 to C8, the Corvette serves as Chevrolet's halo vehicle and is widely
				noted for its performance and distinctive plastic—either fiberglass or composite—bodywork.
			</p>
			<p>
				In 1953, when GM executives were looking to name the new Chevrolet sports car, assistant director for the Public Relations department
				Myron Scott suggested Corvette after the small maneuverable warship—and the name was approved. The first model, a convertible, was
				introduced at the GM Motorama in 1953 as a concept and was followed ten years later by the 1963 second generation, in coupe and
				convertible styles. Originally manufactured in Flint, Michigan and St. Louis, Missouri, the Corvette has been manufactured in Bowling
				Green, Kentucky since 1981.
			</p>
			<p>
				The Corvette has since become widely known as "America's Sports Car." Automotive News said that after 'starring' in the early 1960s
				television show Route 66, the Corvette became synonymous with freedom and adventure," ultimately becoming both "the most successful
				concept car in history and the most popular sports car in history."
			</p>	
		]]>
	</Body>
	<Tags>Car,Sport,Oldtimer,Chevrolet,Corvette</Tags>
	<DisplayTags>False</DisplayTags>
	<CreatedOn>2020-05-29</CreatedOn>
	<DisplayType>10</DisplayType>
  <Image>sportscar.jpg</Image>
	<Comments>True</Comments>
	<SectionBg>dark</SectionBg>
</BlogPost>