<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<BlogPost>
	<Title>The Maldives, the world's lowest-lying country</Title>
	<MetaTitle>The Maldives, the world's lowest-lying country</MetaTitle>
	<Intro>The Maldives, officially the Republic of Maldives, is a small island nation in South Asia, situated in the Arabian Sea of the Indian Ocean. It lies southwest of Sri Lanka and India, about 700 kilometres (430 mi) from the Asian continent's mainland.</Intro>
	<MetaDescription>The Maldives, officially the Republic of Maldives, is a small island nation in South Asia, situated in the Arabian Sea of the Indian Ocean. It lies southwest of Sri Lanka and India, about 700 kilometres (430 mi) from the Asian continent's mainland.</MetaDescription>
	<Body>
		<![CDATA[
			<p>
				The Maldives, officially the Republic of Maldives, is a small island nation in South Asia, situated in the
				Arabian Sea of the Indian Ocean. It lies southwest of Sri Lanka and India, about 700 kilometres (430 mi) from
				the Asian continent's mainland. The chain of 26 atolls stretches from Ihavandhippolhu Atoll in the north to Addu
				Atoll in the south to the equator. Comprising a territory spanning roughly 298 square kilometres (115 sq mi), the Maldives is
				one of the world's most geographically dispersed sovereign states as well as the smallest Asian country by land area and
				population, with around 515,696 inhabitants. Malé is the capital and the most populated city, traditionally called the "King's
				Island" where the ancient royal dynasties ruled for its central location.
			</p>
			<p>
				The Maldives archipelago is located on the Chagos-Laccadive Ridge, a vast submarine mountain range in the Indian Ocean;
				this also forms a terrestrial ecoregion, together with the Chagos Archipelago and Lakshadweep. With an average
				ground-level elevation of 1.5 metres (4 ft 11 in) above sea level, it is the world's lowest-lying country, with even its highest
				natural point being one of the lowest in the world, at 5.1 metres (17 ft).
			</p>
			<h4 class="fs-h4">Historical influences on the Maldives</h4>
			<p>
				In the 12th century Islam reached the Maldivian archipelago, which was consolidated as a sultanate, developing
				strong commercial and cultural ties with Asia and Africa. From the mid-16th-century the region came under the
				increasing influence of European colonial powers, with the Maldives becoming a British protectorate in 1887. Independence
				from the United Kingdom came in 1965, and a presidential republic was established in 1968 with an elected People's Majlis.
				The ensuing decades have seen political instability, efforts at democratic reform, and environmental challenges posed by climate change.
			</p>
			<p>
				The Maldives became a founding member of the South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation (SAARC). It is also a member of the
				United Nations, the Commonwealth of Nations, the Organisation of Islamic Cooperation, and the Non-Aligned Movement.
				The World Bank classifies the Maldives as having an upper-middle income economy. Fishing has historically been the
				dominant economic activity, and remains the largest sector by far, followed by the rapidly growing tourism industry. The Maldives
				rate "high" on the Human Development Index, with per-capita income significantly higher than other SAARC nations.
			</p>
			<p>
				The Maldives was a member of the Commonwealth from July 1982 until withdrawing from the organisation in October 2016 in protest
				at allegations by the other nations of its human-rights abuses and failing democracy. The Maldives rejoined the Commonwealth
				on 1 February 2020 after showing evidence of functioning democratic processes and popular support.
			</p>
		]]>
	</Body>
	<Tags>Nature,Beach,Maldives</Tags>
	<DisplayTags>True</DisplayTags>
	<CreatedOn>2020-10-07</CreatedOn>
	<DisplayType>20</DisplayType>
  <Image>maldives.jpg</Image>
  <ImagePreview>maldives-preview.jpg</ImagePreview>
	<Comments>True</Comments>
</BlogPost>